## Jiazhen Hong

Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering Rutgers University

§ (201) 985-4402

ih1590@rutgers.com

94 Brett Rd, Piscataway, NJ

https://h128jj.github.io/jiazhenhong

#### **Personal Statement**

I am a fourth-year Ph.D. candidate working at the Integrated Systems & NeuroImaging Laboratory, advised by Professor Laleh Najafizadeh. My primary research interests include machine learning, timeseries signal processing, foundation model and Generative AI for brain-computer interfaces (BCIs), and natural language processing (NLP).

#### **Education**

Ph.D. candidate in Computer Engineering

02/2020 - Present

M.S in Electrical Engineering

09/2017 - 01/2019

B.S. in Communication Engineering

09/2012 - 06/2016

Rutgers University, New Brunswick, NJ, USA

GPA:3.9/4.0

Advisor: Professor Laleh Najafizadeh

Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, NJ, USA

GPA:3.9/4.0

Advisor: Professor Shucheng Yu

Jimei & Chung Yuan Christian University, China.

GPA:3.5/4.0

#### **Research & Publications**

# Refereed Journal Papers (Under review)

- [1] **J. Hong**, W. Qian, Y. Chen, and Y. Zhang, "A geometric approach to *k*-means," submitted (In Preparation)
  - [2] **J. Hong**, W. Wang, S. Haghani, and L. Najafizadeh, "Subject-specific Channel Selection Based on Davies- Bouldin Index for EEG Motor Imagery Classification," in preparation.
  - [3] **J. Hong**, W. Wang, and L. Najafizadeh, "A Mind-Controlled Speller System Incorporating NLP Technique and P300-Based Brain-Computer Interfaces," in preparation.

#### **Refereed Conference Papers**

#### (Under review)

[1] **J. Hong** and L. Najafizadeh, "TopoEEG: a TimeSformer-Based Topographic Image Representation Method for Early Single-Trial Detection of P300," submitted.

#### (Accepted/Published)

- [1] **J. Hong**, F. Shamsi, and L. Najafizadeh, "A Deep Learning Framework Based on Dynamic Channel Selection for Early Classification of Left and Right Hand Motor Imagery Tasks," Proc. of 44th Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC'22), Glasgow, Scotland, July 2022, pp. 3550-3553.
- [2] **J. Hong**, L. Najafizadeh, "P3T: A Transformer Model for Enhancing Character Recognition Rates in P300 Speller Systems," 58th Annual Asilomar Conference on Signals, Systems, and Computers.
- [3] **J. Hong**, W. Wang and L. Najafizadeh, "ChatBCI: A Fast P300 Speller Brain-Computer Interface Incorporating Generative AI-Based Word Prediction," 2024 IEEE Brain Discovery and Neurotechnology Workshop. (Spotlight) Machine Learning and Computer Paradigms for Brain Discovery

## **Scholarships and Awards**

IEEE Brain Discovery &
Neurotechnology
09/2024

Travel Award of 2024 IEEE Brain Discovery & Neurotechnology

Workshop.

Rutgers University 05/2024

The best TA of the Semester Award for Fall 2023

### **Working Experience**

Research Intern 09/2024-12/2024	AI/ML Specialist (Foundation Model) @EMOTIV
Course Instructor 06/2022 – 08/2022	Linear Systems and Signals @Rutgers University
Teaching Assistant 02/2020 – 05/2024	Digital Signal Processing @Rutgers University Digital Signal Processing Lab @Rutgers University Linear Systems and Signals @Rutgers University

#### **Technical Skills**

- Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, scikit-learn, Qt5, NumPy, Pandas)
- MATLAB® (EEGlab, Digital Signal Processing toolbox, object-oriented programming)
- Hardware: Brain Products, actiCAP, Raspberry Pi, Arduino, VEX-brain